WILLIAM OTTO

Full Stack Developer

Profile

I'm a Software Developer focused on Mobile and Web development. I have been working as a developer since 2018 for several national and international companies, currently specializing in front-end technologies. I'm a hard working person, always looking for a way to solve problems in a creative and effective way.

Work experience

Freelancer Software Developer

Remote • July 2018 - February 2022

- Create IoT solutions using Python (only 6 months of project)
- Create mobile applications with React Native and web applications with several technologies
- Teach beginner programmers, helping them to learn new technologies
- Work alone or with teams to improve the quality of a project
- Stack: React, React Native, NodeJS, PHP (7.1+), Angular 10+, Jest, Cypress, Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Google Cloud, Heroku

Full Stack Web Developer, Agro1

Erechim, RS, Brazil (hybrid) • January 2021 - June 2021

Context: Company focused on agribusiness, has as its product a site that helps to register planting data, worked on the AgroGestão and Aqila project

- Support developers, always doing pair programming
- Preventive maintenance of the application always responding to customer requests
- Assistance on support tickets
- Hold daily meetings to align team goals
- Stack: Ruby (RoR), React, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Jest, Cypress, Docker

Full Stack Web Developer, Builderall

Remote • July 2021 - February 2022

Context: Digital marketing company, has several projects that help customers in creating an online store, I worked on the project Super Checkout

- Act together with the CEO to align the project objectives
- Plan and execute new features on the application

- Teach trainees developers how to code with Laravel and Vue, always keeping up with them in the process
- Troubleshoot the application
- Lead the team, acting as a SCRUM master and reviewing PR's.
- Stack: PHP (Laravel), Vue (2 and 3), Docker, MariaDB, Jest, Cypress

Frontend Web Developer, Disys

Remote • February 2022 - Present

Context: E-commerce that sells pharmaceutical products, I work on the checkout project, with a team of over 15 developers

- Participate on SCRUM meetings to align team goals
- Plan and execute new features on the application (made with Micro Frontend structure)
- Propose new implementations (Libraries or Frameworks) to solve problems
- Help trainee developers to improve their knowledge professionally
- Stack: Angular 8+, TypeScript, NgRx, Jasmine, Cypress, Storybook, Jest

Education

Atitus Educação Passo Fundo, RS, Brazil February 2021 - August 2022 Bachelor of Computer Science

FIAP

São Paulo, SP, Brazil (Remote) August 2022 - August 2024 Associate Degree on Systems of Internet

Additional Informations

Phone number: +55 (54) 9 8400-0540

Email: williamroberto321@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/william-otto321/</u>

Languages: Portuguese (Native) and English (Advanced)